Rei Bahidi



ABOUT ME

Hello! I'm Rei, a master's student in Computer Science driven by an insatiable curiosity for all things tech. My enthusiasm for computer science is matched only by my commitment to developing secure software solutions. Currently, I specialize in Python within the cybersecurity domain, but my technical repertoire extends to JavaScript and Java, where I've developed fairly learning albeit simple projects using Express.js and SpringBoot.

ADDRESS

Rruga Myslym Shyri Tirana, Albania

PHONE

069 70 32 607

EMAIL

rei.bahidi@outlook.com

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT Python Developer | CYBEROO | Tirana, Albania

- Learned to write readable and well-organized code that sticks to the best conventions such as PEP8, specifically in the context of Object-Oriented Programming, employing some of the best methodologies and code Design Patterns such as SOLID or DRY as well as Factory or Singleton patterns.
- Learned to interact with NoSQL databases such as Neo4j, ElasticSearch, Redis or CouchDB be it firsthand through SQL-like queries or through hand-tailored Python functions.
- Designed and maintained REST APIs according to the best practices, specifically through the FastAPI library.
- Interacted with relatively common projects in the Cybersecurity ecosystem.
- Managed to push my interpersonal skills, considering that I had to interact not only with my surrounding colleagues but also with people from different nationalities, be it physically or through platforms such as Microsoft Teams, thusly expanding my communication and understanding capabilities.
- I learned to understand the Python call stack and follow it properly to triangulate and solve different problems and bugs in relation to the projects.
- Widely used git and specifically GitLab for version control and distribution, be it through CI/CD pipelines or through the git interface.
- I interacted with Linux distributions, particularly with Ubuntu to develop the above-mentioned software, as a result getting well acquainted with how Linux environments work.
- Learned and developed Celery based scripts for managing workers and concurrent tasks.

WEBSITE

www.rei-bahidi.github.jo/homepage/

NOVEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

Intern Data Analyst | OXA Studio | Tirana, Albania

- Interacted with and set up implementations of low code streaming and high-performance data pipelining tools like Apache Kafka and Apache Beam.
- Learned the basics and the general concepts of Python, MongoDB and Docker.
- Wrote data migration and data modeling scripts in Python that interacted with MongoDB.
- I learned what it means to work in an environment that abides to AGILE and SCRUM methodologies.
- Learned the basics of version control systems, namely git.

EDUCATION

University of Tirana | Tirana, Albania

Master's degree in computer science | OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT

Bachelor's degree in computer science | SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2022

COMMUNICATION

As I stated above, through my work in an office environment I have been faced with many situations, a result of the diversity that such environments bring, thus aside from my technical skills I have also improved my people skills. I am confident in my abilities to understand and collaborate with almost anyone in a professional context at the very least. Taking this into account I am sure that my communication and social capabilities will help in efficiently following and solving any problem that may be presented. One aspect in which I am cautious of is putting the work above any interpersonal discrepancies that one might have, this in turn makes the work process easy and fluid.

HOBBIES

I can talk about my hobbies all day considering that I am passionate about my fun-time, but I am going to keep it brief.

One of my longtime hobbies is hiking, I have been hiking for a long time leaving close to no mountains here in Albania which I have not treaded. Aside from hiking I also love other outdoor sports as well such as running or calisthenics. I love exercising and I do so five times a week, which I am careful not to skip unless there is a very valid reason.

Another thing that I have taken an interest as of late is watching movies, some of the latest movies that I have been watching are Ikiru by Akira Kurosawa, The Seventh Seal by Ingmar Bergman and Parasite by Bong Joon-ho. I really like movies from the 1950s. I feel like they're the byproduct of really hard work considering the lack of the technology that we have nowadays.

Reading is another one of my passions, though to be honest I do struggle a bit to read consistently, I am not sure whether this is because of my choice of

books or because of my rather rowdy life. Some books that I have read lately are For Whom The Bell Tolls by Ernest Hemingway and The Psychopathology of Everyday Life by Sigmund Freud, they might be very different genres and completely unrelated to one another but I like the variety.

One more thing that I have been frequently doing is going to the theatre. I have watched plenty of interesting shows such as the Tartuffe by Moliere and King Lear by Shakespear.